2 Read the advertisement, instructions and model below, then look at the CV on the right. Say which information in the CV has not been included in the letter, and why. Finally, suggest alternative beginnings and endings to this letter.

Rapidly expanding marketing company seeks marketing manager for overseas office in Tokyo. The successful candidate should be fully qualified in the marketing field and have a knowledge of the Japanese language. The applicant should be between 30-40 years old, single and willing to relocate at very short notice. All letters, including a CV and one photograph, should be marked for the attention of Mrs Dominique Lloyd (Personnel Manager) CFF Marketing Ltd 7, Brompton Rd, Surrey, Tel.: 8219434

You have decided to apply for the job advertised above. Write your application, stating clearly why you think you are suitable for the job.

Dear Mrs Lloyd,

I am writing to apply for the position of Marketing Manager in your Tokyo office, as advertised in last week's Guardian newspaper on 9th October.

As outlined in my curriculum vitae, which I have enclosed, I attended Riverside Secondary School in Gloucester where I completed my GCSE and 'A' Level studies. In 1987, I graduated from the University of Wales with a BSc in Business Studies and Marketing.

After graduation, I moved to Tokyo where I trained as a market researcher for the Yen Company for two years. On my return to England, I continued working as a market researcher until 1993 when I obtained my present position.

I am currently employed as Assistant Managing Director at Melton Enterprises, where my duties include the organisation of staff and stock, as well as the allocation of budget within the sales department. I am also responsible for overseeing the whole business, and am generally noted for my good organisational and managerial skills.

I believe that I would be an ideal candidate for the position you have outlined, as I have had extensive marketing training with a well-known Japanese marketing and public relations firm. My time spent living in Tokyo also ensured that I obtained a valuable insight into Japanese culture and working practices. I also have a number of very good business contacts in Tokyo, as well as a basic understanding of the Japanese language which is necessary if one is to be able to work effectively. Finally, I am willing and able to relocate at short notice, which I understand to be a requirement of the position.

I enclose my curriculum vitae and photograph as requested, and I would be happy to supply you with further details should they be required. I thank you for considering my application and am willing to attend an interview at any time.

> Yours sincerely, Steven Bradley Steven Bradley

CURRICULUM VITAE

Name: Steven Bradley

Date of Birth: 6 December 1964

Address: 21, Tiffen Avenue, Gloucester

Education/Qualifications:

1976-1983

Riverside Secondary School, Gloucester GCSEs: Maths, Economics, English, Computing, History, Political Science, Japanese, Asian Studies

'A' Levels: Maths (B), Economics (B), General Studies (B), Business Studies (B)

1983-1987

B.Sc in Business Studies — University of Wales

Work Experience:

April 1993 - Sept 1997

Assistant Managing Director, Melton Enterprises, London

Sept 1989 - April 1993

Market Researcher, BLD Services, Oxford

June 1987 - Aug 1989

Trainee Market Researcher, The Yen Company, Tokyo

Other Information:

- Basic Japanese
- Full, clean driving licence
- Interests: sailing, cooking, jogging, karate

Referees:

Carl Spencer (President) BLD Services 2, Downing St, Oxford

Susan Marcus (Managing Director) Melton Enterprises 42, St Catherines St, London

Useful Language: Applying for a Course

Opening remarks:

I am writing to apply for admission to I would like to be considered for a place on

the course in ...

Closing remarks:

I enclose

further details of my education/qualifications to date.

Please find enclosed a copy of my degree/diploma/etc.

I hope that you will consider me for entry/admission to ...

6 First, read the instructions below and underline the key words. Then, read the model and check if all the information required by the instructions has been included. Finally, identify the topic of each paragraph.

You wish to apply for a course of study in Britain. Write a letter of application to the college or university concerned, giving your personal details and your academic qualifications, including your level of English. Include information about the course and subjects you wish to study, and why you have chosen this particular college or university.

Dear Sir/Madam,

I am writing to apply for the Journalism Foundation Course offered by your university for the academic year beginning October, 1998.

I am a 24-year-old French citizen, currently living in Paris. Since leaving school in 1990, I have held a variety of positions working for local newspapers. For the last two years I have been employed as an assistant in the editing department of an English Language newspaper published in Paris.

I am a holder of the Bac. C. as well as having successfully completed a DEUG in English Literature. Furthermore, I have been studying English since the age of 12 and have recently obtained a grade B in

the Cambridge Proficiency in English examination.

I believe that I am well-suited to a career in journalism and I am keen to continue working in this field. However, I feel that I lack the formal qualifications and training necessary to progress beyond my present level of assistant editor. A foundation course would give me an excellent basis for further study, together with an insight into journalism from an international perspective.

Your university has an extremely good reputation in the field of journalism and media studies. The facilities which you offer to students seem both practical and up-to-date. The "Gender and Media" option on your syllabus is of particular interest to me, as is the

opportunity to study in a large city such as London.

Please find enclosed a copy of my CV, giving further details of my educational qualifications and work experience. I hope you will consider my application and I look forward to hearing from you soon.

Yours faithfully, Marcel Martin Marcel Martin

DISCUSS & WRITE

- 7 Look at the following writing task instructions and answer questions below. The questions apply to both tasks.
- a) You have seen an advertisement in the newspaper for the position of Hotel Manager at a popular ski resort. Write a letter of application giving information about yourself, your qualifications and previous experience, as well as explaining why you would be suitable for the job.
- b) You have been studying English for several years in your own country, and feel that you would benefit from an eight-week intensive course for foreign students offered by a college in the south of England. Write a letter applying for a place on the course, stating your reasons for choosing this particular college.
- What greeting would you use?
- What is the main purpose for writing the letter?
- What is/are the additional purpose(s)?
- What paragraph plan would you use?
- What useful expressions could you use as opening and closing remarks?
- How would you sign the letter?



8 Choose ONE of the writing tasks above, and write a complete outline plan with notes. Then write the letter in about 300 words.